#### Abibatu Dora kamara

# abiemos85@yahoo.com

## 84C Bass Street, Brookfield's, Freetown

#### +23279198579/ +23231298433

### **Profile**

A highly organized, detail oriented and dependable media professional with over 10 years' experience. Having exposure to a wide range of journalism, accounting and human right skills, I am able to play key roles in media, accounting and marketing related issues to ensure that quality solutions meet organizational objectives.

#### **Achievements**

- **2020-** Awarded as the Best Female Graduate for Academic Excellence from the Institute of Public Administration and Management (IPAM), University of Sierra Leone
- **2017-**Completed the Reporting on Money Laundering and Counter Financing of Terrorism in summit in Sally, Senegal organized by ECOWAS Inter governmental Agency against Money Laundering and Counter Financing of Terrorism, qualifying me to become a Media Ambassador in championing financial crimes and other related issues in West Africa
- **2015-** Completed a training programme on how to report children issues in Togo, Lome organized by Save the Children
- **2014-** Completed a training on Corruption Reporting organized by the Anti Corruption Commission and its partners
- **2014-** Completed training workshop on how to Report on Women's Reproductive and Health Rights Issues in Kenya organized by IPAS Africa Alliance
- **2013-** Completed an intensive training on News writing and Journalism in Accra, Ghana organized by Deutche Welle based in Germany
- **2012-** Trained on Reporting on Money Laundering and Counter Financing of Terrorism in Monrovia, Liberia organized by ECOWAS Inter governmental Agency against Money Laundering and Counter Financing of Terrorism
- **2010-** Trained on Human Rights Peace and Security in Sweden and Columbia organized by the Swedish International Development Agency (SIDA).
- **2008-** Trained on News gathering and reporting in Accra, Ghana organized by the International Institute of Journalism (IIJ)
- **2008-** Trained on news writing and journalism in Freetown, Sierra Leone, organized by Journalists for Human Rights a Canadian media organization

#### **Abilities**

- High degree of accuracy, initiative and adaptability
- ❖ Capability to confront and follow-through on difficult issues
- ❖ Ability to demonstrate high standard of integrity and positive attitude
- ❖ Ability to work with little or no supervision

## **Experience**

## New Age Newspaper Consultant News Editor 2018

- Proof reading stories for publication
- Representing the organisation on meetings and seminars
- Providing leadership for junior Reporters

## Pinnacle Marketing Consulting Firm Media Assistant 2016-2017

- Planning and project managing marketing events and evaluating their success.
- Evaluating the effectiveness of all marketing activity
- Developing and implementing an internal marketing programme
- Supporting the marketing manager in day to day marketing activities.
- Organizing of meetings between Power for All and the Renewable Energy Association Sierra Leone and other partners

# Media Consultant Office of First Lady 2015 -2017

- planning publicity strategies and campaigns
- dealing with enquiries from the public, the press, and related organizations
- speaking publicly at interviews, press conferences and presentations
- analyzing media coverage
- Developing Media Strategy on the popularization of the Campaign on Accelerated Reduction of Maternal Mortality (CARMMA), an African Union Project for African First Ladies

### Ipas- Sierra Leone Local Media Consultant 2014-2016

- Create a link between the organization and the media, organize media engagement like meetings, workshops and radio and television programmes.
- Do articles for the organization for newspapers and online publication.
- Conduct surveys and documentaries on women and health issues in the country
- Develop a Communication Strategy leading to the repeal of the 1861 Abortion Bill
- Liaise with CSOs, the Media, Parliament and line Ministries on the repeal of the 1861 Abortion Bill
- Do documentaries on unsafe abortion of women and girls and come out with feedbacks from the public with regards the Repeal of the Abortion Bill

- Attend seminars, workshops and also represent the organization in local and international trainings and seminars.
- Compiled stories on a daily basis for publication according to the organization standards
- Sometimes serves as News Editor

## DHL Sierra Leone Local Media Consultant 2014

- Directing public relations campaigns for the company
- Setting up speaking engagements and PR events

### Member Sierra Leone Association of Journalists Ebola Response Committee

- The Ebola Response Committee was charged with the responsibilities of developing and leading the association's response to the EVD in order to complement government's efforts.
- The Committee embarked on a series of interventions, starting with all newspapers donating a daily, quarter page advertising space for Ebola messages and radio stations donating 30 minutes of airtime.
- With the support from the Center for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the Committee trained journalists and bloggers on how to report Ebola Stories

## • Sierra Leone Association of Journalist National Financial Secretary 2013- 2015

- Prepare financial reports
- Present all financial statements to both executive and general membership.
- Present annual financial statements to the Auditors for audit purposes.
- keep all financial records of the Association in strict collaboration with Accounting standards

## Inter-governmental Agency against Money Laundering media Coordinator 2013 And Anti Terrorism (GIABA)

- Organize national and international conferences, workshops and meetings on Money Laundering and Counter Financing of Terrorism
- Liaise with Media and CSOs working on corruption and money laundering issues and give update about financial crimes in Sierra Leone

### **Qualifications**

Bsc (First Class ) Honors Degree in Public Sector Management Institute of Public Administration and Management (IPAM) 2018-2019

## **Interests**

Counseling people

> Reading

> games and sport

working with groups

## Referees

➤ Mr. Christian Charles

Senior Accountant

Association for Rural Development

+23276805526

➤Mr. Ishmael Bangura

Senior Lecturer

Institute of Public Administration and Management (IPAM)

+23277255340